Guide to the Herbert Resnicow Papers RG.024
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Herbert Resnicow Papers
1983-1996
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Resnicow, Herbert
RG.024
24
8 Cubic Feet 8 cartons
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Herbert Resnicow in 2016, on behalf of the Estate of Melly Resnicow.
- Series I: Uncorrected Proofs (bound), 7418
  - Murder Across and Down: A Crossword Puzzle Mystery (2 copies), 1985 June; 7419 (Box 1)
  - Murder at the Super Bowl (2 copies), 1986; 7420 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Curse: A Whodunit, 1986; 7421 (Box 1)
- Series II: Published Monographs (U.S. editions), 7422
  - The Gold Solution: A Whodunit, 1983; 7429 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Deadline: A Whodunit, 1984; 7427 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Frame: A Whodunit, 1984; 7425 (Box 1)
  - The Seventh Crossword, 1985; 7446 (Box 1)
  - Murder Across and Down, 1985; 7445 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Curse: A Whodunit, 1986; 7426 (Box 1)
  - Murder at the Super Bowl (Fran Tarkenton and Herb Resnicow), 1986; 7428 (Box 1)
  - The Crossword Code, 1986; 7443 (Box 1)
  - The Crossword Legacy, 1987; 7423 (Box 1)
  - The Crossword Hunt, 1987; 7444 (Box 1)
  - The Dead Room, 1987; 7431 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Gamble: A Mystery, 1988; 7430 (Box 1)
  - The Hot Place: A Mystery, 1991; 7432 (Box 1)
  - Murder at City Hall (Edward Koch and Resnicow), 1995; 7424 (Box 1)
- Series III: Published Monographs (International editions), 7436
  - The Gold Solution (British edition), 1984; 7434 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Deadline (British edition), 1985; 7433 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Frame (British edition), 1986; 7435 (Box 1)
  - Il Grande Gold (Italian edition), 1984; 7438 (Box 1)
  - Cruciverba con Delitto (Italian edition), 1986; 7442 (Box 1)
  - Cruciverba per un Codice (Italian edition), 1987; 7439 (Box 1)
  - Camera con Morto (Italian edition), 1988; 7440 (Box 1)
  - Il Settimo Cruciverba (Italian edition), 1988; 7441 (Box 1)
  - Caccia al Cruciverba (Italian edition), 1989; 7437 (Box 1)
  - The Dead Room (Japanese edition), 1990; 7447 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Solution (Japanese edition), undated; 7448
  - The Gold Deadline (Japanese edition), undated; 7449 (Box 1)
- Series IV: Loose manuscripts (in boxes), 7450
  - Herbert Resnicow's "The Dark Room" and Herb Aaron's "Diamond in the Dead Room", undated; 7451 (Box 1)
  - The Gold Solution (annotated draft), undated; 7457 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - The Gold Solution (copy edited), undated; 7452 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - The Gold Solution (with corrections), undated; 7458 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - The Gold Solution (photocopied edits), undated; 7460 (Box 2, Item 4)
  - The Gold Solution: A Whodunit (photocopied edits), undated; 7461 (Box 2, Item 5)
  - The Gold Solution (photocopied edits), undated; 7462 (Box 2, Item 6)
  - The Gold Solution (photocopied edits), undated; 7482 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - The Gold Deadline, undated; 7453 (Box 3, Item 2)
  - The Gold Curse, undated; 7454 (Box 3, Item 3)
  - The Gold Curse (in paper bag with note and edits from editor), 1986 July 29; 7464 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - The Gold Curse (corrected manuscript and note from St. Martin's Press editor), 1985 October 10; 7477 (Box 3, Item 5)
  - The Gold Gamble (with notes in brown paper), undated; 7469 (Box 3, Item 6)
  - The Gold Gamble (final manuscript), Red Card (plot summary), and letter from Resnicow to editors (in brown paper), 1987 November 25; 7474 (Box 4, Item 1)
  - The Crossword Code, undated; 7455 (Box 4, Item 2)
  - The Crossword Code (in brown paper), undated; 7472 (Box 4, Item 3)
  - The Seventh Crossword (draft, galleys corrected by Resnicow, and "KCD's copy" in brown paper), 1986; 7473 (Box 4, Item 4)
  - The Seventh Crossword (galleys), undated; 7467 (Box 4, Item 5)
  - The Seventh Crossword (galleys, master, and drafts), undated; 7471 (Box 4, Item 6)
  - The Crossword Legacy (galleys with notes in brown paper), 1986; 7475 (Box 5, Item 1)
  - The Crossword Legacy (in brown paper), undated; 7483 (Box 5, Item 2)
  - The Crossword Hunt (author galleys with note from editors in brown paper), 1987; 7476 (Box 5, Item 3)
  - The Crossword Hunt (in brown paper), undated; 7484 (Box 5, Item 4)
  - A Killing at the Super Bowl (draft), undated; 7478 (Box 5, Item 5)
  - Murder at the World Series (Resnicow and Tom Seaver draft), 1987; 7479 (Box 5, Item 6)
  - Diamond in the Dead Room draft, undated; 7468 (Box 5, Item 7)
  - The Al Baer Series and The Dead Room (Plot Summary), undated; 7480 (Box 5, Item 8)
  - The Dead Room (in brown paper), undated; 7485 (Box 6, Item 1)
  - The Dead Room (in brown paper), undated; 7486 (Box 6, Item 2)
  - The Red Card (drafts, written with Pele), undated; 7465 (Box 6, Item 3)
  - Die Laughing (a Marcy Gabor mystery), 1993; 7463 (Box 6, Item 4)
  - The Spy in My Bed (with loose notes), 1988; 7456 (Box 6, Item 5)
  - The Crossword Trap (oversize in brown paper), undated; 7487 (Box 7, Item 1)
  - Beanball (oversize in brown paper), undated; 7489 (Box 7, Item 2)
  - Beanball, undated; 7488 (Box 7, Item 3)
  - The Hot Place (with note from St. Martin's Press editor), 1990 May 7; 7481 (Box 7, Item 4)
  - The Hot Place (original manuscript with not from St. Martin's Press editor), 1990 November 27; 7470 (Box 6, Item 3)
  - The Case of the Missing Max (And Other Stories), 1994; 7466 (Box 7, Item 6)
  - The Gold Curse (oversize in brown paper), undated; 7490 (Box 7, Item 7)
  - Mixed drafts including "The World's Greatest Architect: A short story", undated; 7459
- Series V: Short Stories and Screenplays, undated; 7491
  - Head Up, 1986; 7492 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - True Witness, 1989; 7493 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - A Few Stories for Mitzi, 1991; 7494 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - The Odds, 1992; 7495 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - D.W.I., 1989; 7496 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - The Christmas Bear, 1993; 7497 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sub Rosa, 1991; 7498 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Typecasting, 1988; 7499 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Good Act, 1990; 7500 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Filial Gifts, 1993; 7501 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Greater Love Than This..., 1987; 7502 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Avenger, 1992; 7503 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Problem: Macy's Window, 1982; 7504 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Problem: Macy's Window, 1991; 7505 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Dog Act, 1990; 7506 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Deconstruction, 1989; 7507 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - The Records Left, 1989; 7508 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Anarch, 1992; 7509 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Nosim, 1992; 7510 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - The Third Conflict, 1993; 7511 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - The Whodunit List, 1993; 7512 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Fatal Oversights, 1993; 7513 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Fairy Godfather, undated; 7514 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Greater Love Than This... (with Alfred Hitchcock Mystery Magazine rejection letter), 1996 October 23; 7516 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Die Laughing Screenplay, undated; 7517 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Die Laughing Screenplay, 4th draft, 1994 June 21; 7518 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Series VI: Notes and Galleys, 7515
  - The Crossword Trap, Notes and Letter, 1968 December 20; 7519 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Red Card draft, undated; 7522 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten notes, undated; 7520 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Super Bowl galleys, undated; 7521 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - 7th Crossword, notes in spiral notebook, undated; 7523 (Box 10, Item 1)
  - Seventh Crossword, notes in spiral notebook, undated; 7524 (Box 10, Item 2)
  - Gold Curse I, notes in spiral notebook, undated; 7525 (Box 11, Item 1)
  - Gold Curse II, notes in spiral notebook, undated; 7526 (Box 11, Item 2)
  - Rules, notes in spiral notebook, undated; 7527 (Box 11, Item 3)
  - The Crossword Legacy I, undated; 7528 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Crossword Legacy II, undated; 7529 (Box 12, Item 2)
  - Untitled, undated; 7530 (Box 12, Item 3)